<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General issues on Bulb Audit</title>
    <link>https://heydon.github.io/bulb-audit/patterns/general/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General issues on Bulb Audit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://heydon.github.io/bulb-audit/patterns/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Color dependence</title>
      <link>https://heydon.github.io/bulb-audit/patterns/general/color-dependence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heydon.github.io/bulb-audit/patterns/general/color-dependence/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Color makes interfaces attractive and can sometimes help to reinforce meaning. For example, red is associated with danger in many Western cultures, and may form part of a &amp;lsquo;delete&amp;rsquo; button&amp;rsquo;s design.
But dependence on color alone to communicate important information runs the risk of alienating a range of users, including those with forms of color blindness, and others with monochrome displays.
In each case color is used to differentiate items, a supplementary alternative method of differentiation should also be present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus styles</title>
      <link>https://heydon.github.io/bulb-audit/patterns/general/focus-styles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heydon.github.io/bulb-audit/patterns/general/focus-styles/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Focus styling, provided by user agents by default, is used to indicate which element is currently being focused by keyboard. Typically, focus is achieved by pressing the Tab key. Pressing Tab should focus the next interactive element in the source, invoking the focus style.
Users who rely on the keyboard for page navigation include those with motor impairments due to long term ailments (such as rheumatism) or temporary injuries (like a broken wrist).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Form errors</title>
      <link>https://heydon.github.io/bulb-audit/patterns/general/form-errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heydon.github.io/bulb-audit/patterns/general/form-errors/</guid>
      <description>Introduction As users attempt to complete forms, it is important they are notified promptly and clearly when they make errors, and are provided with assistance in fixing those errors.
For assistive technology users, completing forms can be especially arduous where one or more of the following are true.
 The invalid state of a field is not communicated The error message is not associated with the field The presence of errors is not communicated on submission  The careful wording of error messages and descriptions is also important, as well as indicating which text is error text without relying entirely on color (see  Color dependence).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heading structure</title>
      <link>https://heydon.github.io/bulb-audit/patterns/general/heading-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heydon.github.io/bulb-audit/patterns/general/heading-structure/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Heading elements are often chosen according to the perceived importance of the text they contain and the sections they introduce. The more &amp;lsquo;important&amp;rsquo; the heading, the higher the heading level and — typically — the larger the font size. An &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt; might be 1.5rem and an &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt; 3rem.
However, headings levels do not simply denote importance, but a hierarchy of page subsections. There are certain rules to creating a hierarchy (or &amp;lsquo;document outline&amp;rsquo;) that should not be broken:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List structure</title>
      <link>https://heydon.github.io/bulb-audit/patterns/general/list-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heydon.github.io/bulb-audit/patterns/general/list-structure/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Along with headings, lists give structure to a web page. They group items together so users know they are related or equivalent.
Assistive technology users find lists especially helpful because most software will identify a list semantically, enumerate its items, and provide shortcuts for navigating between the list items. The NVDA screen reader provides the L shortcut key for navigating between lists, and the I shortcut key for jumping between list items.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Placeholder labels</title>
      <link>https://heydon.github.io/bulb-audit/patterns/general/placeholder-labels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heydon.github.io/bulb-audit/patterns/general/placeholder-labels/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The placeholder attribute is intended for providing supplemental hints and examples for completing a form. It should be used in conjunction with a standard and persistent label, conventionally placed above the input in question.
Where placeholders are used as primary labels, a number of accessibility and usability issues emerge.
Firstly, the placeholder is not supported as an accessible label in legacy browsers and assistive technologies, meaning those users will not hear a label as they focus the control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skip links</title>
      <link>https://heydon.github.io/bulb-audit/patterns/general/skip-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heydon.github.io/bulb-audit/patterns/general/skip-links/</guid>
      <description>Introduction WCAG 2.0 mandates a &amp;lsquo;bypass&amp;rsquo; mechanism to enable users that navigate web pages by keyboard to skip over introductory content and go directly to the main (unique) content of the page. Without such a provision, accessing page content can be time consuming and arduous.
With the introduction of landmark elements like &amp;lt;main&amp;gt;, it has become easier for screen reader users to navigate between the larger sections of the page using software-specific shortcuts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text alternatives</title>
      <link>https://heydon.github.io/bulb-audit/patterns/general/textual-alternatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heydon.github.io/bulb-audit/patterns/general/textual-alternatives/</guid>
      <description>Introduction For blind users, textual alternatives of important visual information must be provided. Composing that text effectively is a question of context.
For example, a logo that is intended as a study in logo design should include a textual alternative — typically via an &amp;lt;img&amp;gt; tag&amp;rsquo;s alt attribute — that describes the features of the logo, such as the colors and typography. For Bulb&amp;rsquo;s logo this might read something like, &amp;rdquo; expressive, hand written text, in white, and featuring hooped ascenders&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wording</title>
      <link>https://heydon.github.io/bulb-audit/patterns/general/wording/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://heydon.github.io/bulb-audit/patterns/general/wording/</guid>
      <description>Introduction It&amp;rsquo;s not enough that elements in a web page&amp;rsquo;s HTML are marked up correctly. Where they provide textual labels, these labels need to be readable and descriptive.
 Headings must clearly describe the sections they introduce Labels for links, buttons and form elements must clearly describe the purpose of those controls Page titles must sufficiently describe the page and its purpose  Since headings and links are aggregated into lists by screen reader software, it is important they make sense independent of context.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>